人身売買
Human trafficking...
本字幕又✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
主に女 子供ね
Mostly women and children.
この国では奴隷すら禁じられてるのに
But slavery is illegal in this country.
奴等の目的はそれだけじゃない
That isn't their only goal.
集めた戦力で
With the forces they've gathered,
長年対峙してきた海賊 私らも確実に潰す気だもんね
they must intend to crush us.
We pirates have opposed them for years.
仕掛けましょうよ こっちから
Let's hit them first!
Don't be hasty.
急ぐんじゃないよ
阿波の港でドンパチやれば 回りの住民にも被害が及ぶ
If we brawl at Awa Port, the residents will be caught in the crossfire.
So we'll attack Kum-ji's ships here,
よって クムジの船を襲うのは
in the waters between Awa and the Kai Empire, where they'll probably make the trade.
取引が行われるであろう戒帝国と阿波の真ん中のこの海域
問題はいつ何時決行するかということと
The question is when they're going to act,
集められた女の子達がどの船に乗っているかだね
and which ships the women will be on.
そう
Right.
クムジは売買に使う人間をそのまま人質としても利用するだろうから
Kum-ji will likely use the people
he's selling as hostages,
無暗には手を出せない
so we can't attack recklessly.
なんとか女達の安全を確保する方法はないものか
Is there any way to secure the women's safety?
でも 大事な取引ってことは
But if it's an important deal,
isn't Kum-ji likely to be there himself?
クムジも現場に来る可能性が高いってことだろう
頭さえ探し出してふんじばれば 早いんじゃないか
Wouldn't it be faster to find
their leader and capture him?
Yeah. After all, we have powerful allies this time!
あ なんてたって 今度の俺らには心強い味方がいるしな
何にしろ もう少し情報が必要だね
Either way, we need more information.
私らにとってもこれは絶交の機会
This is an excellent opportunity for us.
十数年 この阿波の人間を虐げ
We'll beat up Yan Kum-ji and his officials,
who have corrupted Awa and terrorized its people for more than ten years.
腐った町にしたヤンクムジと役人共を何としても打ちのめし
We'll return freedom to this town.
この町に自由を取り戻す
今度は私も剣を取ろう
This time, I'll fight with you.
最後まで私について来な 小僧共
Stick with me until the end, boys!
ギガン船長は 誰も戦わせたくないのに
Captain Gi-gan doesn't want to make anyone fight.
みんな そんな船長を理解し
Her crew understand that, so they muster as much courage as they can.
勇気を振り絞って生きている
この人達の為に 何かしたい
I want to do something for these people.
元気になった本当の阿波の町を 私も見たい
I'd like to see the real Awa, once it's better.
otome yo
O maiden!
akatsuki ni moeagare
Flare up in the dawning sun!
muchi de kayowaku mamorareru dake no
I want to tear off the guise of the ignorant
hime nugisutete watashi wa ikitai
Frail protected princess and live
mukashi yori sukoshi dake suki ni nareta
To conquer the color of the burning dawn
akatsuki no sora no iro nabikase
That I've recently started enjoying
rinzen to tsuyoku
With strength and commanding presence
kedakaku sora wo miagete
I strive to be someone I'm proud of
hokoreru jibun ni narou
And looking up idealistically to the sky
mamori aishi tsuranuku
To protect, to love, to stand my ground
keshite ubawasenai
I won't allow myself to lose anything again
kedakai hana no you ni
Like a noble flower
hitamuki na jounetsu de
With single-minded passion
zankoku na sadame sae
Even if faced with a cruel fate
kirihiraite miseru kara
I will push through
Episode 20:
Chain of Courage
おい 早くしろ
Hey, hurry up!
しっかり前見ろよ
Face forward!
ヨナちゃん いいの いいの
Yona, it's okay.
そうです このような仕事は私めが
That's right. Allow me to handle this.
Huh?
兄ちゃん スゲェな
Man, you're strong.
大したことではない
This is nothing.
ハ ハク
H-Hak!
師匠 武術を 武術を伝授してください
Master, teach me how to fight!
Me too!
俺も 俺も
授業料 一万銀
Lessons cost ten thousand rin.
Huh?!
Seriously? You're so mean!
ユン
Yun...
Hey, you! The one who shouldn't even be alive! Why won't you sit still?
あぁ そこの死に損ない
何で大人しくしてないの いい加減殺すよ
I'll kill you myself.
Yona...
ヨナちゃん
町に偵察に行くんだけど 一緒に来る
I'm going to scout out the town.
Care to come with me?
Amazing!
凄い 緑龍って空飛べるのね
So the Green Dragon can fly?
It isn't so much flying as jumping.
飛ぶっていうか 跳躍だけどね
高いの平気
You don't mind heights?
No.
Even though you were so terrified at the Mist-Shrouded Cape?
雲隠れ岬ではあんなに怖がっていたのに
不思議
It's strange. I feel much closer to you now.
あの時よりずっとジェハを近くに感じるの
Being near you eases my mind.
ジェハの側はほっとする
Curse this infernal dragon blood.
まったく忌々しいね 龍の血って奴は
隠れて
Hide.
なに
What is it?
ヤンクムジだ
It's Yan Kum-ji.
あれが
That's him?
上から見ると この町のいびつさが明るみに出るね
From up here, it's clear how twisted the city is.
Huh?
女子供は
When Kum-ji comes,
クムジが来ると目を付けられないよう 家の中に隠れるんだ
women and children hide in their homes to avoid attracting his attention.
What's wrong?
どうしたの
具合でも悪いの
Are you ill?
I-I'm fine.
べ 別に
君
You...
は 離せ
L-Let go!
落としましたよ お嬢さん
You dropped this, miss.
どう どうして分かったんですか
H-How could you tell?
あえて言うなら匂い
If I have to give a reason, your scent.
You pervert!
やだ 変態
成程 これが変態
I see. So this is a pervert.
役人から逃れるために男装を
You disguised yourself as a man
to escape the officials?
Y-Yes.
はい
But you seemed extraordinarily frightened.
それにしたって さっきの君は怯え方が尋常じゃなかったね
何があった
Did something happen?
役人 いや クムジから何かされた
Did the officials... No, did Kum-ji do something to you?
分からないんです 分からないんです
I don't know! I don't know!
A few days ago, my friend and I heard there was a decent job...
数日前に 割のいい仕事があるという噂を聞いて
私と友人はとある店に入ったんです
so we went into a certain shop.
My friend was very beautiful.
友人はとても綺麗な子でした
私と友人は中に通されましたが
We were allowed inside,
最終的には 友人だけが奥の部屋に呼ばれました
but ultimately, only my friend
was called to the back room.
私は帰っていいと言われたのですけど
They told me I could leave,
何か気になって彼女の入っていた 狭い部屋を見たんです
but I was curious, so I looked inside the small room she'd gone into.
一瞬でした
It happened in a flash.
あの子はあれから二度と帰って来ません
She hasn't come back since.
後から あの店はヤンクムジ様の店だと知って
Later, I learned the shop
belonged to Yan Kum-ji.
私 それからは役人達が怖くて
Since then, I've been afraid of the officials.
間違いないな それは人身売買収容所への入り口だ
That must be the entrance to the human trafficking detention facility.
いくつかあるうちのね
One of many, that is.
Huh? Human...
人身...
Y-You don't mean...
ま まさか
大丈夫 君の友達は無事だ きっと戻ってくる
Don't worry. Your friend is fine.
I'm sure she'll come back.
よしよし 可哀想に よほど怖かったんだね
There, there. Poor girl.
It must've been quite scary.
Wipe your tears. I'll do something about it.
涙を拭いて 僕がなんとかするから
それまで女を隠し 家でじっとしているんだ
Until then, disguise yourself
and hide in your home.
いやいや 本当は男装なんて勿体ないんだけど
Normally, it would be a waste
for you to dress like a man,
but it's the only way to fool those idiots.
アホの目を誤魔化す為にはそれしかない
And once I save her, will you
introduce me to your friend?
そして無事助けられたら是非そのお友達も紹介してくれないか
君さえ良ければ今度...
If you like, maybe someday...
Yum! This is great!
うめぇ 最高
当然
Of course it is.
海の幸タップリの特性海賊汁
It's my special pirate soup, full of seafood.
具材も贅沢に使ったから 美味しくないはずないもんね
I went all-out with the ingredients, so there's no way it isn't good.
This is delicious!
うめぇな これ
Tremble
Wh-What sort of insect is this?
こ こ こここれは何の虫だ
Tremble
That's a crab!
それは蟹だ
Tremble
シンア見習って何でも食え
Follow Sin-ha's example and learn to eat anything!
Tremble
From a place where he had to eat anything to survive.
本当にうめぇぞ 坊主
This really is good, kid.
Be my bride.
嫁に来い
やだよ 定職に就いていない破落戸なんて
No way. I'm not marrying an unemployed bum.
Thunder Beast, the food is ready.
雷獣 食事だよ
なに空にがん飛ばしてんの
Why are you glaring at the sky?
ところで 俺の蜂蜜知らない
By the way, have you seen my honey?
Man, this pirate soup really warms you up.
いや あったまるな 海賊汁 ユン君天才
Yun, you're a genius.
プッキュウかな
Maybe the squirrel took it.
ヨナ
Yona...
船長 恐らく決行の日は明後日の夜だ
Captain, they'll probably act the night of the day after tomorrow.
The day after tomorrow?
明後日
根拠は
What makes you say so?
売買する人間を集める店を見つけたんだ
I found a store gathering people to sell.
そこは表向きには女性に割のいい仕事を提供している
Outwardly, they offer decent jobs to women.
だが実際は高く売りそうな女をどこかに搬送する場
But they're actually sending women
who will fetch a high price somewhere.
いつまで仕事を募っているのか 人伝に聞いたところ
I asked one of the shop workers how long they'd be recruiting,
店の者は明後日 昼までと答えたそうだ
and the answer was until the afternoon of the day after tomorrow.
クムジは欲深い
Kum-ji is greedy.
いい商品があるなら ぎりぎりまで待つだろう
If there are quality goods available,
he'll wait until the very last minute.
つまり 取引を行うのはこの日
In other words, he'll make the deal on that day.
船を動かすなら 日が落ちた夜中
He'll send his ships after dark.
しかし どの船に女達が乗せられるが分からないね
But we don't know which ship
the women will be on.
内側から
From inside...
女の人達が乗った船の内側から
花火のようなものを打ち上げれば
If we launch something like fireworks
from inside the ship the women are on,
少しでも早く救出できるかしら
would it be possible to rescue them faster?
それはそうだが 誰が打ち上げるんだい
Yes, but who's going to launch it?
私が
I will.
I'll infiltrate the ship and set off fireworks.
私が潜入して  船から花火を打ち上げます
Yona!
ヨナちゃん
今回の目的は クムジを倒す以上に
Isn't our priority saving the women rather than defeating Kum-ji?
売買される女達を無事救うことでしょう
乗せられた船を逸早く見つけて
We must find the ship they're on quickly and take them to a safe place.
安全な場所へ避難させる
そのために 私が忍び込んで 船の場所を知らせるから
To do that, I'll sneak onto the ship and signal you where they are.
待って
Wait.
それはちょっとお勧めしねぇな
I wouldn't recommend that.
He's right. It's too dangerous.
そうです 危険すぎます
クムジや役人の本拠地に入り込むなんて
You can't enter Kum-ji and his officials' stronghold.
俺も反対
I'm against it too.
ユン
Yun...
Launching fireworks would involve
花火を打ち上げるって事は
火薬を持ち込みつつ捕えられてる船の中から
見張りの目を掻い潜り甲板に出るって事だよ
sneaking past the guards onto the ship's deck while carrying gunpowder!
見つかったら殺されるよ 絶対無理
If they find you, they'll kill you!
There's no way!
大体 持ち込めるくらいの小さな火薬で
Besides, it will be difficult to signal us with fireworks small enough for you to carry on board.
味方に気づかせるのは無理がある
恐らく 俺等も戦闘中だ
We'll probably be fighting too.
シンアなら 遠くても 私の合図に気づくはず
But Sin-ha should be able to see
my signal from far away.
Yeah, but...
だからって
一つ一つの船の中を調べる時間はないわ
We don't have time to search every ship.
戦ってる間に 女達が戒帝国に渡ったら手遅れ
If the women reach the Kai Empire
while we're fighting, it will be too late.
そうならないように
I'm the only one who can sneak aboard
with the women to secure their safety, right?
女達の中に入って安全を確保するのは
私にしか出来ない仕事でしょう
Captain Gi-gan,
ギガン船長
私にも 戦わせてください
let me fight with you.
この娘は
This girl...
世の中の修羅など知らずに育ったようでいて
She was raised far from this world's conflicts,
時折 戦場を駆ける戦士のような目をする
but sometimes, she has a seasoned warrior's eyes.
この私が圧倒されるとはね
I can't believe she's overpowering me.
確かに 成功すれば確実に女達を助けられる
If you succeed, we will indeed
be able to rescue the women.
船長
Captain...
正し 一人では無謀だよ
But you can't go alone.
作戦成功の為に もう一人くらい潜入させないと
We must send at least one more
if we are to succeed.
俺が
I'll go.
私が
I will go.
Just so you know, it has to be someone who can pass for a woman.
言っておくが 女装しても見れる容姿の奴だよ
What?
なんと
なにしろ クムジ自慢の商品だからね
These are Kum-ji's prized goods.
他の女にひけを取らない美しさじゃないと 門前払いだろうさ
If you aren't at least as beautiful as the other women, you'll be chased off.
俺が
I'll go.
私が
I will go.
僕が
I'll go.
人の話を聞いてないのか まさかの自信か
I can't tell if you're not listening
or are just really confident.
ごついのがもう一人増えてるし
I have another brawny volunteer now too.
まぁ むさい男共の中で唯一可能なのは...
Amidst all these filthy men,
the only possible candidate is...
Huh?
お前なら機転も利くし 火薬も扱えるだろい
You're sharp, and you know
how to handle gunpowder.
W-Wait a minute!
ちょ ちょっと待ってよ
確かに女装したらその辺の子には負けないよ
It's true that I'm beautiful
when I'm disguised as a woman.
美少年だから
After all, I'm a handsome young man.
でも相手は悪徳領主
But we're dealing with an evil lord.
ヨナが行くのだってまだ反対してるんだよ
I'm still opposed to Yona going.
俺が加わっても成功するかどうか
There's no telling whether we'll
succeed even if I join her.
まぁ 火薬を扱うなら 俺が行くしかないよね
Well, if we're using gunpowder,
I guess I have to go.
ユン
Yun...
ったく めんどくさい 明日までに準備しなきゃ
What a pain in the butt.
I'll have to prepare before tomorrow.
ヨナ 安心していいよ
Yona, don't worry.
俺 負ける戦には出陣しない主義だから
I don't fight losing battles.
The deal is the day after tomorrow.
取引は明後日
We'll infiltrate them tomorrow.
潜入作戦は明日決行だ
お前達 作戦を練るよ
Let's come up with a battle plan.
Yeah!
ありがとう
Thank you.
なにが
For what?
For listening to my request.
私の願いを聞き入れてくれて
私は今回の作戦に必要だと思っただけさ
I merely thought it was necessary for our plan.
捕えられてる女達は
恐怖で希望を失ってるだろうから
The captured women must be
feeling terrified and hopeless.
お前が守ってやるんだよ
You have to protect them.
はい
I will.
今度の戦闘はうちもただじゃ済まない
This battle will cost us as well.
私はいつも彼奴らに無茶を言ってるからね
I always ask too much of them.
相手を殺さずに懲らしめるなんて
容易にできることじゃない
Beating your enemies without killing them isn't easy.
大丈夫よ ハク達がいるから
It'll be fine. You have Hak and the others.
お前も 決して命を粗末にしてはいけないよ
You mustn't waste your own life, either.
船に乗せたら お前はもう私の娘みたいな者だから
Once I let you on the ship,
you became like a daughter to me.
勝手に死ぬことは許さないよ
I won't allow you to just go off and die.
どうした
What's wrong?
私は母上の記憶があまりないの
I don't really remember my mother.
でも 貴方を見ると 言葉を聞くと
But seeing and listening to you...
その厳しさと優しさに 涙が出てきます
Your strictness and kindness bring tears to my eyes.
母と言うのは こんな感じなのかなって
I wonder if this is what a mother is like.
懐かしくて とても胸が痛くて
It brings back memories that make my chest hurt.
どうしたら 止めてくれますかね
How can I convince you not to do this?
Hak...
ハク
クムジのところに行くのが
どれ程危険か 分かってんですか
Do you have any idea how dangerous going to Kum-ji will be?
どうしてそんな 無謀なことばかりするんですかね
Why are you always so reckless, Princess?
このお姫様は
時々 縛り付けておきたくなんだよ
Sometimes, I wish I could tie you up.
ど 退きなさい ハク
M-Move, Hak!
ハク
Hak, I thought Kouka Kingdom was a peaceful and prosperous place.
私は
高華国は平和で豊かな国だと思っていたの
父上が望むように
A kingdom without conflict where everyone smiled,
just like my father wanted.
争いがなく 人々が笑っている国だと
But the Fire Tribe lands and the Port of Awa haven't changed since my father's rule.
でも
火の部族の土地や 阿波の港は
父上の治世から変わっていない
父上が間違っていたかどうかなんて
I'm still not sure if my father was wrong or not.
まだ私には分からない
でも
But I'm just as responsible for
allowing the Fire Tribe lands
火の部族の土地や この町をこんな風にしてしまった責任が
and this town to end up this way.
私にもある
貴方は知らない
You don't know.
城に居たくせに 知らないの
You lived in the castle, but you don't know?
知ろうとも 知りたいとも 思わなかった
I never tried to learn what my responsibilities were or even wanted to.
私の責任
だから私は戦うの
That's why I must fight.
行かせて ハク
Let me go, Hak.
どうかしている
Something's wrong with me.
絶対に行かせたくねぇってのに
I know I don't want to let her go, but...
武者震いか
Am I shaking with excitement?
あんなヨナ姫を 俺は知らない
I don't know this Princess Yona.
もっと知りたい
I want to know more.
もっと
More...
俺は 姫さんが成功させちまうのが見たいんだ
I want to see the princess succeed.
ヨナちゃん 可愛い 一発合格
Yona, you're so cute.
You'll nail it.
I'll do my best.
頑張るわ
Go become Kum-ji's lover!
そのままクムジの愛人になってこい
当然 正妻にだって勝つよ
You know it. I'll best his actual wife, even.
ユン 火薬は
Yun, do you have the gunpowder?
帯の中に仕込んでる
It's inside my sash.
針金の先に火薬を括り付けてる
I rubbed gunpowder on the end of a wire.
小さくても高く飛ぶ特製花火
It may be small, but it'll fly high.
From here, just stick to the plan.
じゃ あとは手筈通りに
Okay. We're off-
はい では行ってきま...
Don't you have anything with longer sleeves?
もっと袖の長い服はないのか
無理だよ兄ちゃん その手隠すのは
It's impossible to hide that hand, mister.
No, Ki-ja. It is funny, though.
ダメよキジャ 面白いけど
この腕がもう少し小さければ
If only this arm were smaller...
問題はそこじゃないわ
That isn't the problem.
ユン
Yun...
雷獣 合図したら早く助けに来てよね
Thunder Beast, once we give
the signal, come rescue us.
大丈夫か
Are you okay?
なにか
What do you mean?
情けないと思う
You think I'm pathetic because Yona's so brave, but I'm shaking?
ヨナが気丈なのに 俺が震えてるなんて
でもね だからこそ俺はいいんだ
That's what makes me the best choice.
誰よりも慎重に 誰よりも見苦しく生きていた
I've lived more carefully and
wretchedly than anyone else.
誇れるほどにね
I'm proud of it.
Thunder Beast, it's okay.
雷獸 大丈夫よ
俺が行くからには 絶対にヨナは死なせない
Because I'm going along, I can guarantee that Yona will not die.
任せる
I'm counting on you.
ここで働きたいと
You want to work here?
そうなんです 凄く待遇もいいって聞いてますし
Yes. We heard the pay is really good.
いいでしょう 大歓迎です
Very well. We'd be delighted to have you.
嬉しい よろしくお願いします
I'm so happy.
I look forward to working here.
奥へどうぞ
Come inside.
こりゃ上玉だ
These girls are beautiful!
こちらでお待ちください
Wait here.
今 店主を連れてきますから
I'll get the manager.
ついに来た
We're here.
これを開けたら
Once we open this door...
では 暫くお待ちを
Wait here a moment.
足が 震えてる
My legs are shaking?
今更
Now?
ヨナ
Yona...
決戦まで 後一日
One day until the battle.
暗くて長い夜の始まりだった
It was the beginning of a long, dark night.
modoranai hibi ni namida koboshite
Crying tears for the days that won't return
miageta sora ga akaku akaku moeru
You look up to the sky, and it's burning bright red
jibun no tsuyosa yowasa kizuketa no nara ima
Now that you know your own strength and weakness
kimi yo osoreruna kokoro omomuku mama
You should have no fear and go where your heart takes you
kaze wo kirisusumu sono tabiji wo
Cleaving through the wind, your path is lit
akatsuki ga terasu
By the dawn
(tsudoe takeki kaina)
(Gather, fierce arm)
(senri no hitomi)
(All-seeing eyes)
sora wo kakeyuku ashi
Feet that dash through the sky
(kuon no tate)
(Shield of eternity)
inishie no chikai ima hatashite
Fulfill the ancient vows
yoru yo akete yuke
O night, break into dawn
Next Time
確かに私は 何の力もありません
I may not be strong, but please let me fight,
でもどうか 戦わせてください
一人の人間として
like any other human being.
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 21:
次回 暁のヨナ 第二十一話
Episode 21:
Spark
Spark.
火花